MEGAN GILPIN

New York, New York 10031

T: (620) 481-1538

E: megangilpin@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/megan-gilpin

Github: github.com/megangilpin

Portfolio: megangilpin.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer at the intersection of functionality and design with 10 years of experience developing creative consumer-focused products. Highly skilled communicator and project manager who works well in fast-paced environments with tight deadlines. Driven by an underlying passion for innovation to pursue full stack web development through the Columbia Engineering Boot camp.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, node.js, Express.js **APPLICATIONS:** Git, Heroku, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Word, Excel, PowerPoint

PROJECT

ARRYVL - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/MEGANGILPIN/FINITO | HTTPS://ARRYVL.HEROKUAPP.COM

Full stack MERN app that, with a click of a button, will track the user's location and share it with a friend. Arryvl maps the user's route as they head to their destination and informs those they care about once they have arrived.

- Created with Mongo DB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Google Maps API, Twilio, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.
- Core responsibilities included developing logo and initial prototype in Adobe XD, creating Google Map API calls, establishing back-end routes, built front-end to display user's journey to friend.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ORIGINAL PENGUIN - NY, NY 2014 - PRESENT

DESIGNER | OUTERWEAR/SUIT SEPARATES

- Oversee concept, design, and production of the global assortment; 450 skus per year in over 30 countries.
- Maximized outerwear sourcing and design to improve margin by 10% within the first year, consecutively achieved new maximum target margin per sku in all following years.
- Implement bottom category relaunch, resulting in 83% growth in bottoms share of the total sales mix.
- Present concepts and designs to internal teams, including an annual presentation to an audience of over 200.

Kenneth Cole - NY, NY 2009 – 2014

ASSOCIATE DESIGNER | OUTERWEAR/SUIT SEPARATES | 2014 - 2014

- Assisted in growing Reaction business form 150 Macy's doors to Macy's all doors.
- Managed CAD designer to ensure optimal productivity.
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to interpret selling results, sku plans, and design calendar to create product within given price ranges and time frames.

ASSOCIATE DESIGNER | MENSWEAR | 2009 - 2014

- Communicated with overseas agents in over 5 countries through all stages of development and production.
- Created, organized, and maintained all technical packages.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE / COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY - 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js & React.

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS/ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF ART - CHICAGO - 2009